Finding Aid for the Lawrence Morton Papers LSC.1522
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Research Material
  - Boulez, Pierre
    - Boulez, Pierre--Messagesquisse pour 7 violoncelles., 1977. (Box 103)
    - Boulez, Pierre--Improvisation sur Mallarme [I]: le vierge, le vivace et le bel aujourd'hui... pour soprano, harpe, vibraphone, cloches et 4 percussions P., 1958. (Box 103)
      Partition.
    - A file of documents relating to Boulez--1987: UCLA. (Box 127)
  - Cassette Tapes (Audio)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    - Cassette tapes (audio)--Works by Boulez, Ligety, Stravinsky, John Morton, J.D. Zelenka and Vaclav Masek. (Box 78)
      Live performances.
    - Cassette tapes (audio)--Works by Boulez, Stravinsky, Carter, Reynolds, Bartok et al.Stravinsky conducting in U.S.S.R. Boulez talks at Symphony space and New York farewell ceremony. (Box 79)
  - Copland, Aaron
    - Mellors, Wilfred, Hugo Cole, David Matthews, Douglas Young and Norman Kay--Homage to Copland., 1970. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Winter) 95.
      Issue devoted to Copland.
    - Copland, Aaron--The new music (1900-1960)., 1968. (Box 95)
      New York: W.W. Norton & Company, Incorporated.
      Inscribed front paste-down endpaper: For Lawrence Affectionately Aaron January 1968.
    - 1. Clipping file--Copland, Aaron. (Box 98)
      Also includes programs and program notes.
    - Copland, Aaron--Threnody II In memoriam: Beatrice Cunningham., 1973.; Reproduction from transparencies. (Box 126)
      Three copies in box 126.
    - Copland, Aaron--Threnody II In memoriam: Beatrice Cunningham., 1973.; Holograph ink on transparencies. 7 leaves. (Box 126)
      Also 1 leaf holograph list of corrections in partsin L.M.'s hand.
      See correspondence with Copland in Box 2.
  - Craft, Robert
    - Craft, Robert--Boulez and Stockhausen., 1958. (Box 14)
      The Score: A Musical Magazine (November) no.24: 54-62.
    - Transcribed correspondence (spiral notebooks and ring binders) (Box 118)
    - Transcribed correspondence (spiral notebooks and ring binders) Books by Craft. (Box 119)
    - Books by Craft. Articles by Craft (NYRB). (Box 120)
    - Evenings on the Roof (Hume), 1952-1953. (Box 121)
      Miscellaneous. Photographs. Published articles. Reviews--Correspondence with Stravinsky 1944-1954. Catalog of manuscript 1949. Memories and commentaries, corrected proofs. Correspondence with Stravinsky (photos, 9 envelopes).
    - Correspondence with L.M., 1953-1982. (Box 122)
  - Evenings on the Roof (Monday Evening Concerts)
    - Organizational Material. Agreements, clippings, etc., 1946-1948 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Organizational material. Reports., 1941-1950 (Box 131, Folder 2)
      Bound and unbound reports.
    - Production material. Programs (kept separately by Lawrence Morton), 1953-1954 (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Research and ephemeral material. Invitations, notes, etc., 1957, 1961, 1986, and undated (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - Research and ephemeral material. Mailings, typed notes, incl. lists: concert halls, ticket prices, concert dates, etc., 1936, 1939 - 1984 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Research and ephemeral material. Tickets., circa 1947 - 1952 (Box 131, Folder 6)
    - Production Material. Programs "First six months"., 1939 April - September (Box 130, Folder 1)
    - Production material. Programs., 1939 October - 1940 September (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - Production material. Programs., 1940 November - 1941 November (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - Production material. Programs., 1942 (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Production material. Programs., 1943 (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Production material. Programs., 1944 January - May (Box 130, Folder 6)
    - Production material. Programs., 1944 - 1945 (Box 130, Folder 7)
    - Production material. Programs., 1945 - 1946 (Box 130, Folder 8)
    - Production material. Programs., 1946 - 1947 (Box 130, Folder 9)
    - Production material. Programs, incl. concerts by New Friends of Old Music., 1947 - 1948 (Box 130, Folder 10)
    - Production material. Programs., 1948 - 1949 (Box 130, Folder 11)
    - Production material. Programs., 1949 - 1950 (Box 130, Folder 12)
    - Production material. Programs., 1950 - 1951 (Box 130, Folder 13)
    - Production material. Programs., 1951 - 1952 (Box 130, Folder 14)
    - Production material. Programs., 1952 - 1953 (Box 130, Folder 15)
    - Production material. Programs., 1954 - 1955 (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Production material. Programs., 1955-1956 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Production material. Programs., 1956 - 1957 (Box 132, Folder 3)
    - Production material. Programs., 1957 - 1958 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Production material. Programs., 1958 - 1959 (Box 132, Folder 5)
    - Production material. Programs., 1959 - 1960 (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - Production material. Programs., 1960 - 1961 (Box 132, Folder 7)
    - Production material. Programs., 1961 - 1962 (Box 132, Folder 8)
    - Production material. Programs., 1962 - 1963 (Box 132, Folder 9)
    - Production material. Programs., 1963 - 1964 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Production material. Programs., 1964 - 1965 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Production material. Programs., 1965 - 1966 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Production material. Programs., 1966 - 1967 (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - Production material. Programs., 1967 - 1968 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Production material. Programs., 1968 - 1969 (Box 133, Folder 6)
    - Production material. Programs., 1969 - 1970 (Box 133, Folder 7)
    - Production material. Programs., 1970 - 1971 (Box 133, Folder 8)
    - Production material. Programs., 1971 - 1972 (Box 133, Folder 9)
    - Production material. Programs., 1972 - 1973 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Production material. Programs., 1973 - 1974 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Production material. Programs., 1974 - 1975 (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Production material. Programs., 1975 - 1976 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Production material. Programs., 1976 - 1977 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Production material. Programs., 1977 - 1978 (Box 134, Folder 6)
    - Production material. Programs., 1978 - 1979 (Box 134, Folder 7)
    - Production material. Programs., 1979 - 1980 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Production material. Programs., 1980 - 1981 (Box 135, Folder 2)
    - Production material. Programs., 1981 - 1982 (Box 135, Folder 3)
    - Production material. Programs., 1982 - 1983 (Box 135, Folder 4)
    - Production material. Programs., 1983 - 1984 (Box 135, Folder 5)
  - General Books
    - Mann, Thomas--Doctor Faustus: The life of the german composer Adrian Leverkuhn as told by a friend., 1948. (Box 93)
      Translated from the German by G.T. Lowe-Porter.
      Includes L.M's index to musicians and works mentioned in the text. Insert A.S.'s letter and T.M.'s response in Saturday Review (1 January 1949). Reviews from Tomorrow, Time, The Nation & The New Yorker.
    - Carter, Elliott--The writings of Elliott Carter: An American composer looks at modern music., 1977. (Box 95)
      Compiled, edited, and annotated by Else Stone and Kurt Stone.
      Bloomington & London: Indiana University Press.
      Inscribed front paste-down endpaper: For Lawrence my friend Elliot November 5, 1977.
    - Chase, Mildred Portney--Just being and the piano., 1981. (Box 95)
      Foreward by Lee Strasberg.
      Culver City (California): Peace Press, Incorporated.
      Inscribed on the half title: To Lawrence Morton--with great respect and deep appreciation for your warm encouragement. Sincerely, Mildred.
    - Babitz, Sol--Principles of extensions in violin fingering., 1947. (Box 102)
      Philadelphia, Los Angeles, New York: Delkas Music Publishing Company.
      Inscribed: To Lawrence without whose friendship and encouragement this book would not have been given to him. Sol October 1948.
  - General Clipping Files
    - Popular music (Jazz, swing, etc.). (Box 86)
    - Electronic music. (Box 86)
    - China. (Box 86)
    - Government sponsorship. WPA. New York City Center. (Box 86)
    - Germany. (Box 86)
    - General semantics. (Box 86)
    - Acoustics. (Box 86)
    - Amateur music. (Box 86)
    - American federation of musicians Petrillo, James C.--labor conditions. (Box 86)
    - American music., (2 envelopes). (Box 86)
    - Armed forces, music in. OWI. (Box 86)
    - Arranging, editing, etc. (Box 86)
    - Art and Society. (Box 86)
    - Austria. (Box 86)
    - Ballet. (Box 86)
    - Radio. (Box 86)
    - Canada. (Box 86)
    - Holland. (Box 86)
    - Colombia. (Box 86)
    - Commercialism. (Box 86)
    - Composers' rights--Royalties, fees protective organizations, copyright. Composers' economics. (Box 86)
    - Conducting. (Box 86)
    - Criticism. (Box 86)
    - Czechoslovakia. (Box 86)
    - DNA. (Box 86)
    - Economics. (Box 86)
    - Education. (Box 86)
    - France. (Box 86)
    - Foundations. (Box 86)
    - Folk music. (Box 86)
    - Film music. (Box 86)
    - Brazil. (Box 86)
    - Melodrama. (Box 86)
    - Politics, Music and. (See: Art and society, USSR, Shostakovitch, Collaboration. (Box 86)
    - Poland. (Box 86)
    - Performance. (Box 86)
    - Palestine. (Box 86)
    - Overture. (Box 86)
    - Opera. (Box 86)
    - Music for the masses. (Box 86)
    - Modern Music. (Box 86)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 86)
    - Mexico. (Box 86)
    - Metropolitan Opera Company. (Box 86)
    - Great Britain. (Box 86)
    - Publicity. (Box 86)
    - Greece. (Box 86)
    - Local Artists. (Box 86)
    - Library. (Box 86)
    - League of Composers. Modern Music Magazine. (Box 86)
    - Latin America. (Box 86)
    - Korea. (Box 86)
    - Jewish music. (Box 86)
    - Japan. (Box 86)
    - Italy. (Box 86)
    - International Society for Contemporary Music. (Box 86)
    - Hungary. (Box 86)
    - Hollywood Bowl. (Box 86)
    - Recording. (Box 86)
    - Recitalists. (Box 86)
      Piano: Casadesus, Horowitz, Rosenthal, Paderewski, Petri, Schnabel, Gieseking.
      Cello: Casals. Etc: Adler, Kell, Landowska.
      Violin: Busch, Heifitz, Huberman, Kreisler, Milstein, Virvai.
      Ensembles: Pro Arte, Paganini Quartet, Guller Quartet.
      Singers: Melchior, Teyte, Anderson, Robeson.
    - Cowell, Henry. (Box 87)
    - D: Dallipicola, Davidovsky, Delius, Dello Joio, Dessau, Del Tredici, Dittersdorf, Dubensky, Dukas, Dukelsky, Dvorak, Dyson. (Box 87)
    - Davies, Peter Maxwell. (Box 87)
    - Sacred music. (Box 87)
    - Beecham, Sir Thomas. (Box 87)
    - Borodin, Alexander. (Box 87)
    - Bach, Johann Sebastian (2 envelopes). (Box 87)
    - B: C.P.E. Bach, Alexei Balakireff, Marion Bauer, Arnold Bax, William Bergsma, Georges Bizet, Arthure Bliss, Charles Boone, Nadia Boulanger--Easley Blackwook, Arthur Berger, Lennox Berkeley, Paul Ben-Haim and Earle Brown, Frank Bridge, Feruccio Busoni, Robert Russel Bennet, Harrison Birtwistle, Franz Biber. (Box 87)
    - Auric, Georges. (Box 87)
    - Antheil, George. (Box 87)
    - Barber, Samuel. (Box 87)
    - Bartok, Bela. (Box 87)
    - Switzerland. (Box 87)
    - Science. (Box 87)
    - Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague. Coolidge foundation. Coolidge festival. (Box 87)
    - Scandinavian countries. (Box 87)
    - A: Joseph Achron, Isaac Albeniz, Francis Alfano, Danielle Amfitheatof, Edward Applebaum. (Box 87)
    - Beethoven. (Box 87)
    - Bruckner, Anton. (Box 87)
    - Chopin. (Box 87)
    - Chavez, Carlos. (Box 87)
    - Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario. (Box 87)
    - Casals, Pablo (Prades festival, 1950. (Box 87)
    - C: Cavalieri, Andre Caplet, Cornelius Cardew, Caccini, W.W. Cadman, J.A. Carpenter, Alfredo Casella, J.J. Castro, Chadwick, E. Chausson, Luigi Cherubini, Paul Chihara, Chiani, A. Corelli, Henry Cowell, P. Creston, Ruth Crawford, Crumb. (Box 87)
    - Berg, Alban. (Box 87)
    - Brodetsky, Julian. (Box 87)
    - Britten, Benjamin. (Box 87)
    - Brahms, Johannes. (Box 87)
    - Bloch, Ernst. (Box 87)
    - Blitzstein, Marc. (Box 87)
    - Bernstein, Leonard. (Box 87)
    - Berlioz, Hector. (Box 87)
    - Cage, John. (Box 87)
    - L: Levant, Liszt, Lopatnikoff, Lalande, Lutoslawski, Lee, Luzzaschi, Levy, Liebermann, Liadoff, Ligeti. (Box 88)
    - Kirchner, Leon. (Box 88)
    - Lloyd, John. (Box 88)
    - M: Malipiero, Mascagni, Maidena, Maderna, Martin, Machaut, Mathieu, McPhee, Meyerbeer, Mennin, Messiaen, Miaskowsky, Migriome, Mills, Moross, Moore. (Box 88)
    - Mahler, Gustav. (Box 88)
    - Martinu, Bohuslav. (Box 88)
    - Mendeslssohn, Felix. (Box 88)
    - Menotti, Gian-Carlo. (Box 88)
    - Messiaen, Olivier. (Box 88)
    - Milhaud, Darius. (Box 88)
    - Monteverdi. (Box 88)
    - Moussorgsky, Modeste. (Box 88)
    - Kern, Jerome. (Box 88)
    - N: Nabakoff, Nicolas, Nordoff, Nordheim, Nobre. (Box 88)
    - Dreiser, Theodore. (Box 88)
    - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus., (2 envelopes). (Box 88)
    - Gershwin, George. (Box 88)
    - Debussy, Claude. (Box 88)
    - Vega, Aurelio de la. (Box 88)
    - D'Indy, Vincent. (Box 88)
    - Durrell, Lawrence. (Box 88)
    - Dvorak, Antonin. (Box 88)
    - E: Enesco, Einem, Egk, Lehman Engel, J.C. Eloy. (Box 88)
    - Eisler, Hans. (Box 88)
    - Elgar, Sir Edward. (Box 88)
    - Eliot, T.S. (Box 88)
    - F: Faure, Farwell, Fernandez, Ferrari-Trecato, Feldman, Felciano, Filippi, Frorick, Freed, Fricker, Fuleihan. (Box 88)
    - De Falla, Manuel. (Box 88)
    - Hemingway, Ernest. (Box 88)
    - G: Gassman, Ginastera, Glazunov, Glinka, Gluck, Glenville-Hicks, Glass, Gould, Gounod, Goehr, Gretchinov, Gretry, Grieg, Gruenberg, Griffes., Guarnieri. (Box 88)
    - K: Kabalevsky, Kaplan, Kenne, Khatchaturian, Koday, Kraft, Kubik, Kohs, Kurke, Kagel, Klebe, Kohn, Kahn, Kay. (Box 88)
    - Gesualdo. (Box 88)
    - H: Handel, Haieff, Hahn, Harrison, Halffter, Herrmann, Henze, Helm, Helps, Holst, Hovhaness. (Box 88)
    - Harris, Roy. (Box 88)
    - Haydn, Joseph. (Box 88)
    - Heinsheimer, H.W. (Box 88)
    - Henze, Hans Werner. (Box 88)
    - Hindemith, Paul., [2 envelopes]. (Box 88)
    - Honegger, Arthur. (Box 88)
    - Hovhaness, Alan. (Box 88)
    - I: Ibert. (Box 88)
    - Ives, Charles., (2 envelopes). (Box 88)
    - J: Jacobi, Jolivet, Janacek, Jolas, Johnson (Lochram), Johnstone (Arthur). (Box 88)
    - Foss, Lukas. (Box 88)
    - Diamond, David. (Box 88)
    - Strauss, Richard. (Box 89)
    - Schuman, William. (Box 89)
    - Schumann, Robert. (Box 89)
    - Sessions, Roger. (Box 89)
    - Shaw, George Bernard. (Box 89)
    - Shostakovitch, Dmitri., (2 envelopes). (Box 89)
    - V: Vivaldi, Varese, Valen. (Box 89)
    - Stockhausen, Karlheinz. (Box 89)
    - S: Saminsky, (L), Sauget, Samuel, Schnabel, Schuetz, Schmitt, Schuller, Schwartz, Schat, Scriabin, Serly, Shapiro, Shulman, Skalkotlas, Shifron--Still, Strong, Starer, Stevens, St.-Saens, Subotnick, Swanson, Siegmeister, Smetana, D.S. Smith, Smit, Sollberger, Stamitz. (Box 89)
    - T: Tansman, Taylor, Tiomkin, Takahashi, Takemitsu, Tcherepnine, Tchemberdji, Telemann, Thomas (A.), Thompson (R.), Toch, Tremblay, Trimble. (Box 89)
    - Tschaikowsky, Peter Ilyitch. (Box 89)
    - Thomson, Virgil. (Box 89)
    - Thomson, Virgil (Articles not in books). (Box 89)
    - Toscanini, Arturo. (Box 89)
    - Tovey, Sir Donald. (Box 89)
    - U: Ussachevsky. (Box 89)
    - Sibelius, January. (Box 89)
    - R: Rathaus, Respighi, Revueltas, Reger, Rieti, Robertson, Rogers, Roldan, Rorem, Rosenthal (Manuel), Roussel, Ruggles. (Box 89)
    - Nono, Luigi. (Box 89)
    - Orff, Carl, Okeghem. (Box 89)
    - Nielsen, Carl. (Box 89)
    - P: Pisk (Paul), Piston, Pizzetti, Paganini, Paz, Perosi, Penderecki, Phillips, Powell, Purcell. (Box 89)
    - Partch, Harry. (Box 89)
    - Picasso, Pablo. (Box 89)
    - Schubert, Franz. (Box 89)
    - Prokofiev, Sergei. (Box 89)
    - Satie, Erik. (Box 89)
    - Rachmaninoff, Sergei. (Box 89)
    - Rameau. (Box 89)
    - Ravel, Maurice. (Box 89)
    - Riegger, Wallingford. (Box 89)
    - Rochberg, George. (Box 89)
    - Rossini, Gioacchino. (Box 89)
    - Santayana, George. (Box 89)
    - Poulenc, Francis. (Box 89)
    - Xenakis, Janis. (Box 89)
    - Rosza, Miklos. (Box 89)
    - Y: Yun, Isang. (Box 89)
    - Vaughan Williams, Ralph. (Box 89)
    - Whitman, Walt. (Box 89)
    - Webern, Anton. (Box 89)
    - Weber, Carl Maria von. (Box 89)
    - Wagner, Richard. (Box 89)
    - W: Walton, Ward, Weill, Weinaberger, Weiss, Wellesz, Willson, Wolf (Hugo), Wolf (Kenneth), Wolpe, Wolf-Ferrari, Wuorinen. (Box 89)
    - Villa-Lobos, Heitor. (Box 89)
    - Verdi, Giuseppe. (Box 89)
    - Walter, Bruno. (Box 89)
    - Veblen, Thorstein. (Box 89)
    - Z: Zador, Zeisl, Zimmermann. (Box 89)
    - Haggin, B.H. Music on the Radio--New York Herald-Tribune., 1947-48. (Box 98)
    - Metropolitan Opera--Opening. (Box 98)
    - Berg--Lulu. (Box 98)
      Includes programs.
    - Carter, Elliott. (Box 98)
    - Krenek. (Box 98)
      Includes articles and programs.
    - Schoenberg. (Box 98)
      Articles and Program notes. In L.M.'s hand: Whole collection of Schoenberg clippings given to Schoenberg Institute, July 1978.
  - Inscribed Scores, Not Stravinsky
    - Boone, Charles--Starfish., 1966.; Reproduced from transparencies. (Box 101)
      Inscribed on title page: for L.M. with best regards CB. September 20, 1966.
    - Boone, Charles--Etude for Alicia Kristina., n.d.; Reproduced from transparencies. (Box 101)
      Inscribed: Hello there Lawrence Morton! Charles March 24th.
    - Miroglio, Francis--Projections pour quatuor a cordes en hommage a Joan Miro., 1981. (Box 101)
      London: Universal Edition Limited.
      Inscribed: A Lawrence Morton qui realism la premiere americaine de cette partition en signed 'amitie' Francis Miroglio Los Angeles 15 Mai 1981.
    - Kurtag, Gyorgy--Attila Jozsef--Fragments for soprano solo op.20., 1984. (Box 101)
      Budapest: Editio Musica Budapest.
      Inscribed: To Lawrence Morton his true Gyorgy Kurtag.
    - Kraft, William--In memoriam Igor Stravinsky for violin and piano 1972/74., 1974.; Reproduced from transparencies. (Box 101)
      Inscribed: Lawrence--it is more than a pleasure to give this copy to you.... Happy 75th! Bill 9/16/79.
    - Boone, Charles--Raspberries., n.d. (Box 101)
      New York: Edition Salabert.
      Inscribed: For Lawrence--Have I given you one of these already? Charles 13 July '74.
    - Vega, Aurelio de la--Interpolation for solo clarinet (with or without pre-recorded sound elements)., 1965. (Box 101)
      New York: Broadcast Music Incorporated.
      Inscribed: For Lawrence Morton, without whose love and devotion contemporary music in Los Angeles would not be the same Aurelio de la Vega Summer, 1965.
    - Samuel, Gerhard--Paul Blake--Ikon maker., 1979.; Reproduced from transparencies. (Box 101)
      Text by Paul Blake.
      Inscribed on title page: For Lawrence with much love--Gary.
    - Krenek, Ernst--Three lessons for four part chorus of mixed voices a cappella. 3. Geography lesson., 1972. (Box 101)
      For Lawrence Morton.
      New York: Rongwen Music, Incorporated.
      Insert photocopy of manuscript inscribed after dedication [for Lawrence (Morton)]: with all good wishes affectionately Ernst.
    - Noon, David--Trope opus 34 for cello solo., Reproduced from transparencies. (Box 101)
      Inscribed on cover: 8.IV.1975 for Lawrence DN.
    - Boone, Charles--A cool glow of radiation., 1966.; Reproduced from transparencies. (Box 101)
      Inscribed: January 6, 1967 Happy New Year, Lawrence! Charles.
    - Gilbert, Pia--Bells for soprano and piano., 1984.; Reproduced from transparencies. (Box 101)
      Inscribed on front cover: This copy for Lawrence Morton with admiration and love, Pia.
    - Dahl, Ingolf--Quodlibet on American folk tunes (The fancy blue devil's breakdown) for 2 pianos, 8 hands., 1957. (Box 102)
      New York: C.F. Peters Corporation.
      Inscribed on title page: For Larry's collection this little counterpoint exercise[sic], with love from Ingolf April 24, 1958.
    - Smit, Leo--At the corner of the sky for chorus of men and boys (or women) with solo flute, oboe, and speaker., 1981. (Box 102)
      New York: Carl Fischer, Incorporated.
      Inscribed inside front cover: For Lawrence, friend, comrade--in--arms, and essential man--about--music. As ever, Leo 2/19/82.
    - Boone, Charles--San Zeno/Verona., 1976. (Box 102)
      Paris: Editions Salabert.
      Inscribed: For San Lorenzo/Los Angeles* *for good times here, there, & everywhere. Charles.
    - Vega, Aurelio de la--Legend of the Creole Ariel for cello and piano., 1955. (Box 102)
      New York: Peer International Corporation.
      Inscribed on title page: To Lawrence Morton, who so devotedly has fought historical battles for music. Aurelio de la Vega Los Angeles, June, 1958.
    - Berio, Luciano--Tempi concertati per flauto principale, violino, due pianoforti ed altristrumenti., 1962. (Box 102)
      Inscribed on title page: Dear Lorenzo LB.
    - Dahl, Ingolf--Duettino concertante (1966) for flute and percussion., 1968. (Box 102)
      New York: Alexander Broude, Incorporated.
      Inscribed on cover Dear Larry--Ingolf March 1968.
    - Dahl, Ingolf--Concerto a tre for clarinet violin and cello., 1952. (Box 102)
      New York: Arrow Music Press, Incorporated.
      Inscribed: To Lawrence--with thanks for his friendship, his understanding, his good company--Ingolf.
    - Kubik, Gail--Miles Standish choral profile (1948) for mixed chorus and piano., 1950. (Box 102)
      Poem by Stephen Vincent Benet.
      New York: Southern Music Publishing Company, Incorporated.
      Inscribed on cover: Why Lawrence--I didn't know you were related to Tom Morton--regards. always, Gail New York 1950.
    - Stalvey, Dorrance--Points-Lines-Circles., 1978. (Box 102)
      New York: Editions Salabert.
      Inscribed: For Lawrence, my dear and good friend Dorrance 4/12/79.
    - Kohn, Karl--Recreations for piano, four hands., 1973. (Box 102)
      Inscribed on title page: For Lawrence, a souvenir from our Rochampton and Nella Road days, with affection. Karl.
    - Kohn, Karl--Birthday piece., 1979.; Photocopy. Extra copies. (Box 102)
    - Eloy, Jean-Claude--Equivalences pour 18 instruments., 1965. (Box 102)
      Paris: Heugel & C.
      Inscribed on dedication page: ... et a Lawrence Morton, with my sentiment sinceres J.C. Eloy.
    - Samuel, Gerhard--The relativity of Icarus for voice and instrumental ensemble., 1974. (Box 102)
      Poem by Jack Larson.
      New York: Belwin-Mills Publishing Corporation.
      Inscribed on title page: For Lawrence with deep regrets for moving so far from him--Gary July 76.
    - Rozsa, Miklos--For every thing there is a season., 1951. (Box 102)
      Wiesbaden: Briekopf & Hartel.
      Inscribed on title page: For Lawrence from Miklos 1952.
    - Amy, Gilbert--Diaphonies pour double ensemble de douze instruments., 1965. (Box 102)
      Paris: Huegel & C.
      Inscribed on title page: a Monsieur Lawrence Morton con sympathie Gilbert Juin '65.
    - Amy, Gilbert--Inventions pour flute, piano (celesta), harpe, vibraphone (Marimba)., 1965. (Box 102)
      Inscribed on title page.
    - Holliger, Heinz--Erde und himmel (1961) kleine kantate nach texten von Alexander Xaver Gwerder fur tenor, flote, violine, viola, violoncello und harfe., 1963. (Box 102)
      Autographed on title page.
    - Diamond, David--Fourth symphony., 1949. (Box 102)
      New York: G. Schirmer, Incorporated.
      Inscribed on title page: For Lawrence: Inventor of the Greatest 'Peep-show' (among other great inventions). with humble respect and admiration. David Diamond Happy New Year! 1950.
    - Smit, Leo--Copernicus narrative and credo for four-part chorus of mixed voices, narrator and instrumental ensemble., 1982. (Box 102)
      Text by Sir Fred Hoyle.